<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Statistical Musings</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Statistical Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Conversion Modeling for Portuguese retail bank</title>
      <link>/project/conversion-portuguese-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/conversion-portuguese-bank/</guid>
      <description>Part I - Exploratory Data Analysis Business Understanding Data Understanding Data Dictionary Verifying Data Quality Simple Statistics Visualize Attributes Explore Joint Attributes Explore Attributes and Prediction Class Extra features  Extras Rejecting the bank: what are the odds?   Part II - Customer Conversion Modeling with Logistic Regression Data Cleaning and Perform 1 hot encoding on categorical data Training and Testing Split Logistic Regression Model Improvement - Upsampling Test Train Split and Upsampling Results Interpretation of the parameters with the highest weights on the final model: Conclusion     Authors: Robert Hazell, Gavin Hudgeons, Bruce Lee  import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns import matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Capital BikeShare Ridership</title>
      <link>/project/forecasting-capital-bikeshare-ridership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/forecasting-capital-bikeshare-ridership/</guid>
      <description>Capital BikeShare docking station  Introduction I love to bike, especially during the spring and summer. As a New York City resident the city affords miles of urban bike paths, my favorite being the seamless connection between Riverside and Hudson River parks. Of course thousands (if not millions) of others enjoy biking throughout the country, and if you don’t own a bike you can rent one through various bike programs, like NYC’s Citi Bike and Washington DC’s Capital BikeShare (CB henceforth).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>