<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>time series on Statistical Musings</title>
    <link>/tags/time-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in time series on Statistical Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/time-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing WHO health data better than the WHO</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-world-bank-health-data-better-than-the-world-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-world-bank-health-data-better-than-the-world-bank/</guid>
      <description>Can we do better than this? The World Health Organization (WHO), in coordination with the World Bank, maintains data on a variety of topics, including global health care expenditure. They’ve recorded data between 2000 and 2017 on how the world spends its money on healthcare. Here’s their actual data viz.
Figure 1: WHO visualization on global health spending between 2000 and 2017. Source: WHO 
This hardly looks like an effective visualization by Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic’s standards in her book Storytelling with Data, so let’s see how we can improve this to better align with her advice on effective visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Capital BikeShare Ridership</title>
      <link>/project/forecasting-capital-bikeshare-ridership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/forecasting-capital-bikeshare-ridership/</guid>
      <description>Capital BikeShare docking station  Introduction I love to bike, especially during the spring and summer. As a New York City resident the city affords miles of urban bike paths, my favorite being the seamless connection between Riverside and Hudson River parks. Of course thousands (if not millions) of others enjoy biking throughout the country, and if you don’t own a bike you can rent one through various bike programs, like NYC’s Citi Bike and Washington DC’s Capital BikeShare (CB henceforth).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>