<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Statistical Musings</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Statistical Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Art with Python and Tkinter</title>
      <link>/project/galaxy-art-with-python-and-tkinter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/galaxy-art-with-python-and-tkinter/</guid>
      <description>p.caption { font-size: 0.8em; }  How’d you do that? I’d like to give a walkthrough on how I created the visual you see below. It took some pretty serious tinkering, but it’s not too shabby right?
Figure 1: The final output of my galaxy visualization 
 The secret life of galaxies I’ve been working on Lee Vaughan’s excellent book Impractical Python Projects, and Chapter 10 really caught my attention since I’ve always marveled at the heavens and its celestial bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing a Portuguese retail bank&#39;s marketing efforts</title>
      <link>/project/conversion-portuguese-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/conversion-portuguese-bank/</guid>
      <description>Business Understanding Data Understanding Data Dictionary Verifying Data Quality Simple Statistics Visualize Attributes Explore Joint Attributes Explore Attributes and Prediction Class Extra features  Extras Rejecting the bank: what are the odds?    import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns import matplotlib.pyplot as plt # using a relative path would probably be better! bankingDF = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;/Users/roberthazell/Desktop/SMU/ML1/bank-additional-full.csv&amp;quot;) Business Understanding The Bank Marketing Data Set from the UCI Machine Learning Repository was selected to be analyzed by our group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>